I'm going to give you over 10 years of web design knowledge in just 7 minutes.
たった7分で、10年以上分のウェブデザインの知識を全部お伝えします。
No fluff, just the good stuff.
要点だけ、無駄話ナシ。
Are you ready?
準備はいい？
Let's go.
行きましょう。
You can basically boil all the design knowledge that you need to build great websites down to just three things.
優れたサイトを作るのに必要なデザインの知識は、結局3つに集約できます。
Layout, color, and typography.
レイアウト、カラー、そしてタイポグラフィです。
Probably heard it said before that people read or engage websites in somewhat of an F pattern.
人はWebサイトを見るとき、Fパターンで視線を動かすと聞いたことがあるでしょう。
So they start reading at the top left and then they go right, they come back, they go down on the left, they go right, they come back and they go down on the left until they're done.
左上から右へ、また左に戻って下へ、そして右へ…というF字型に読み進める、というやつです。
But here's the truth.
でも実際は違います。
That's actually bogus.
それはほとんど神話です。
It's outdated information that web designers just kind of keep repeating, and so everybody thinks it's true.
昔の説をデザイナーが繰り返しているだけで、いつの間にか定説になっているんです。
I might have been one of those web designers, and for that I apologize.
正直、僕もその一人だったかもしれません。すみません。
The truth is, is that people engage with websites and all sorts of different patterns, and forcing them to pay attention in an F pattern might actually cause them to miss important information.
実際にはユーザーの視線パターンは千差万別で、Fパターンに合わせると重要な情報を見逃させることさえあります。
So what do you do instead?
では代わりにどうする？
You use something called visual hierarchy.
答えは「ビジュアルヒエラルキー」です。
Probably seen an image before where there's this big bold line of text that says you're going to read this first, and the smaller line underneath it that says then you'll read it next.
大きく太い文字で「まずこれを読む」、その下にやや小さく「次にこれ」と示す画像、見たことありますよね。
And then this really tiny line that's all the way in the left hand corner that says, and you'll read this last, that is visual hierarchy.
さらに隅に極小文字で「最後にこれ」とある──それがビジュアルヒエラルキーです。
You make the most important elements of a section, the biggest and the boldest.
最重要要素は一番大きく、一番目立たせる。
And then for each other element that isn't maybe as important, you turn down the volume.
重要度が下がる要素ほど視覚的ボリュームを絞ります。
You make it more inconspicuous for your call to action or buttons.
CTAやボタンを目立たせるために、他の要素は控えめに。
You want to make sure that they have a high degree of contrast from everything else around them.
つまり周囲と十分なコントラストを持たせる必要があります。
Why?
なぜか？
Because the main thing we want people to do on a website is click a button.
ユーザーにしてほしい一番の行動はボタンをクリックすることだからです。
If it doesn't stand out, it's going to make it harder to do that.
目立たなければ行動は起こりません。
And please, I beg of you, stop using ghost buttons.
お願いです、ゴーストボタンはやめましょう。
What are ghost buttons?
ゴーストボタンって何？
They're buttons that just have an outline without a solid background.
背景が透明で枠線だけのボタンのことです。
The problem is that people don't see them and they don't click on them.
ユーザーがボタンと認識せず、クリックしないのが問題。
For colors, every website should have a color palette that matches the brand of the website owner.
カラーについて。どのサイトにもブランドに合ったカラーパレットが必要です。
Here's a few important things to consider when it comes to color.
色選びで大切なポイントをいくつか挙げます。
The first thing is accessibility.
まずはアクセシビリティ。
If you pick colors that make it difficult to read text or tough to see elements clearly, it's going to be hard for users to engage.
読みにくい色や要素が見づらい配色では、ユーザーが離れてしまいます。
You want to pick colors that have a high enough contrast that even users with visual impairments are still going to be able to see things clearly.
視覚障害のあるユーザーでも見やすいよう、十分なコントラストを確保しましょう。
How do you know if a contrast is high enough?
コントラストが十分かどうか、どう判断する？
Something that I like using is a website calledcoolers.co.
僕がよく使うのは「coolors.co」というサイトです。
You could actually take all of the brand colors from a website and put it into the dashboard.
ブランドカラーを入力し、Color Contrast Checkerをクリック。
Click on the color contrast teller and it will instantly tell you which colors pass and which super helpful tool.
どの組み合わせが基準を満たすか一目で分かります。本当に便利。
Another good rule of thumb for colors is that you want to use a guideline called the 6030 ten rule.
もう一つの目安は「60‑30‑10ルール」です。
Basically what this means is that about 60% of your website should use your dominant colors, things like Grays or blacks and whites.
約60%を支配色（グレーや黒・白など）に。
30% you should reserve for your brand colors, and then another 10% you want to use something for an accent.
30%をブランドカラー、残り10%をアクセントカラーにします。
So helping things really stand out.
これで重要な要素が際立ちます。
That's a great thing to use for, like your calls to actions or your buttons.
アクセントカラーはCTAやボタンに最適です。
Is this a hard and fast rule that you absolutely have to use every single time?
絶対遵守のルールではありませんが、
No, but it's a good principle to stick with, especially when you're first getting started.
特に初心者のうちは意識すると失敗しにくい指針です。
Then there's typography.
さて、次はタイポグラフィ。
Typography is one of the most underrated design elements of a website, but it has a massive impact on the readability and user experience.
タイポグラフィは過小評価されがちですが、可読性とUXに大きく影響します。
Thankfully, there's a ton of great options when it comes to fonts.
幸いフォントの選択肢は山ほどあります。
You've got serifs, you've got sans serifs, you've got handwritten fonts, You've got scripts, you've got display, you've got monospace, and it goes on and on.
セリフ体、サンセリフ体、手書き風、スクリプト、ディスプレイ、モノスペース…と枚挙にいとまがありません。
There are three main text elements to consider for your website.
サイトで考えるべきテキスト要素は主に3つ。
You've got your H ones or your main headers, and this should be the biggest, most prominent text on the page.
まずH1（メインヘッダー）。ページで最も大きく、目立たせます。
This is going to describe what the entire page is all about.
ページ全体が何を扱うかを示します。
Then you've got your H2 or your subheadings.
次にH2（サブヘッダー）。
These act as ways to divvy up the rest of the page and guide a user's attention.
ページを区切り、ユーザーの視線を誘導します。
Then finally you've got your paragraph text or your P tags.
最後に本文（Pタグ）。
You don't want to use really decorative text for this.
ここには装飾的すぎるフォントを使わないこと。
It might look cool, but it kills readability.
見た目はカッコいいかもですが、可読性が死にます。
But here's the thing.
でもここで大事なのは、
Good design without good conversion practices doesn't actually help your clients.
デザインが良くてもコンバージョンを考えていなければクライアントの役に立たないこと。
I designed a website a while back for a client and the result was way better than their old website.
以前クライアントのサイトを作り替えたとき、出来栄えは完璧でした。
It was clean, it was modern, it was chef's kiss.
クリーンでモダン、まさにシェフズキス。
The problem was, when we launched it, sales plummeted.
でも公開したら売上が激減。
Why did that happen?
なぜか？
It's because I tried to make it look pretty instead of focusing on good conversion practice.
見た目を優先し、コンバージョンの原則を無視したからです。
If your design doesn't consider conversion, it's useless to your clients.
デザインがコンバージョンを考慮していなければ無価値。
So what are good conversion practices?
では良いコンバージョン施策とは？
Good conversion is all about reducing friction for users.
ポイントはユーザーの摩擦を減らすこと。
You want to make it stupid easy for the users to find what they're looking for and to go through and either buy a product or sign up for a service.
欲しい情報をすぐ見つけ、購入や申込みまでを「バカみたいに簡単」にする必要があります。
And that's done through clarity.
鍵は明確さ。
You want to be crystal clear about who the company is or the person is, who owns the website, and what the user is supposed to do next.
このサイトは誰のもので、次に何をすべきか──徹底的に明確にします。
Why they should even You also do it through scan ability.
なぜ気に留めるべきかまで伝える。そして「スキャンしやすさ」も重要。
People aren't reading websites, they're scanning through it.
人は文章を読むのではなく、ざっとスキャンしています。
So you need to set things out in such a way that people can bounce around and make decisions.
視線が飛びやすく、すぐ判断できる配置にしましょう。
And then finally, you want the website to be motivating.
さらに「動機付け」も欠かせません。
It's not just enough to be pretty.
きれいなだけでは不十分。
You actually need to speak to the heart of the user.
ユーザーの心に響くメッセージが必要です。
Speak to the thing that's driving them to say yes or no.
「買う／やめる」を決める動機に訴えましょう。
But overall, you want to design for the right audience, not for yourself and not for your client.
まとめると、自分やクライアントではなく「正しいオーディエンス」のためにデザインすること。
It doesn't matter if you love the design.
自分が気に入るかどうかは関係なし。
It doesn't even matter if your client loves the design.
クライアントが気に入るかどうかさえ重要ではありません。
Who does it matter for?
大事なのは誰？
The website visitors.
サイト訪問者です。
So do a little research.
ですから調査を。
Who's actually using this website.
実際に使うのは誰なのか。
Fonts, colors, layout.
フォント、カラー、レイアウト──
Choose them based on the target audience and not personal preference.
すべてターゲットユーザーを基準に選びましょう。
Finally, make sure that you never stop learning.
そして学びを止めないこと。
Web designers don't age like fine wine, OK?
ウェブデザイナーはワインのように熟成しません。
We age like a loaf of bread left on the counter.
カウンターに置いたパンのようにすぐ古くなります。
We go stale unless we keep learning.
学び続けなければカビてしまう。
The web design industry is changing fast, and it's going to continue to do so.
業界の変化は早く、これからも加速します。
What worked just five years ago might not work today.
5年前に通用したことが今日は通用しないかも。
It might not work in the next five years.
もちろん5年後にも通用しません。
And if you don't challenge yourself and stay updated, you're going to fall behind.
挑戦し、アップデートし続けないと取り残されるだけ。
Will AI take all of our jobs?
AIが僕らの仕事を全部奪う？
Probably not.
たぶんそこまではない。
But will AI take lazy web designer jobs?
でも「怠けたウェブデザイナー」の仕事は？
Absolutely.
間違いなく奪われます。
The only way to stay valuable is to keep learning, keep adjusting, and keep leveling up.
価値を保つ唯一の方法は、学び、適応し、レベルアップし続けること。
And you might be asking yourself, that's all well and good, but what do I need to do if I'm getting started today?
「今日から始めるなら何をすればいい？」と思っているかもしれません。
Thankfully, I've got another video that I'm going to link to that's going to answer just those questions.
それに答える別の動画を用意しているので、リンクをチェックしてください。
Make sure that you like this video if it was helpful, and be sure to subscribe so that you don't miss another episode.
役に立ったら高評価とチャンネル登録をお忘れなく。
And don't forget, if you don't quit, you win.
そして「やめなければ、勝ち」です。